Braswell Kenneth Azu Junior

(Software Engineer)

I am a Software Engineer with experience in solution design and implementation of technical software projects. Exploration is one of the things which makes me keep learning and growing. I am currently the maintainer of <u>GLab Documentation</u> for the <u>GLab project</u>. I have an interest in building, design and animating user interfaces.

Domain Knowledge

- Software Engineering
- User Interface / User Experience Design

Technical Skills

- Javascript [ReactJs (Next.js) / VueJs (Nuxt.js) / Node.js / TypeScript / React Native]
- CSS [Sass / Scss / Bootstrap / Tailwindcss]
- Golang [Encore / Fibre]
- UI DESIGN [Figma / Adobe XD]
- Git
- API [REST / Graphal]
- Database [MongoDB / Postgres / MySQL]
- Devops [Docker]
- Others [Firebase / Supabase]

Languages

- English
- French (Elementary Level).

Education

- General Science

Kumasi High School 2014 - 2017

- B.Sc Computer Science and Engineering

University of Mines and Technology 2018 - 2022

Professional Experience

Sep 14, 2018 - to date : Freelance Software Developer

- Build websites and web applications for institutions and startups with the sole responsibility of ensuring clients are satisfied and requirements are met.

May 14, 2017 – August 31, 2018 : Vivo Energy, Shell Ghana - Customer Technical Assistant

- Assist and recommend solutions for customers.

April 20, 2021 - November 12, 2021 : The Hive, Kumasi - Software Engineering Intern.

- Build and design software systems to satisfy users' needs.
- Design User Interfaces to be implemented into mobile for the frontend and mobile application teams.

November 1, 2022 - to date : Solar Taxi, Accra - Software Engineer.

- Build and design software systems to satisfy users' needs.
- Plan and solutions for software projects.
- Design and implement backend APIs for web and mobile applications.

Self Studies

- Computer Science Distilled Learn the art of Solving Computational Problems, 2017 (Wladston Ferreira Filho).
- **Eloquent JavaScript** A modern introduction to Programming, 3rd edition (Marijn Haverbeke).
- **Digital Gold** Bitcoin and the inside stories of the Millionaires trying to invent Money (Nathaniel Popper).
- How to design better UI Components Best UX and UI practices when designing UI components, elements, and effects (Adrian K).

Contact and Address

linkedin.com/in/braswell-kenneth-870827192 | github.com/braswelljr | braswellkennth99@amail.com | braswellir.engineer | +233500181106